<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mac | Junda Ong]]></title>
  <link href="http://samwize.com/blog/categories/mac/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://samwize.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-09T16:07:31+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://samwize.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Junda]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[junda@just2us.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac Right Click using Keyboard Shortcut]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/06/09/mac-right-click-using-keyboard-shortcut/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-09T15:59:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/06/09/mac-right-click-using-keyboard-shortcut</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you to be more efficient with computers, you must use the keyboard more than the mouse.</p>

<p>For Mac, it remains a mystery why there isn't a built-in keyboard shortcut for "right clicking". As of Jun 2013, with Mountain Lion, we still lack that.</p>

<p>However, there is a <a href="http://superuser.com/questions/93937/keyboard-shortcut-to-right-click-in-mac-os-x">workaround</a>. But it is recommended only for Mac users with a <strong>separate numpad</strong>.</p>

<p>Luckily I chose to have a Apple Keyboard with Numeric Keypad for my new 27" iMac..</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Go to:</p>

<pre><code>System Preferences &gt; Accessibility &gt; Mouse &amp; Trackpad &gt; Enable Mouse Keys
</code></pre>

<p>Press <code>Control+5</code> for right click.</p>

<p>Achievement Unlocked: Shortcut Ninja!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show hidden files in Finder for Mountain Lion]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/05/27/show-hidden-files-in-finder-for-mountain-lion/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-27T22:20:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/05/27/show-hidden-files-in-finder-for-mountain-lion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can show hidden files in Finder on your Mountain Lion (or any Mac OS).</p>

<p>On Terminal, run this:</p>

<pre><code>defaults write com.apple.Finder AppleShowAllFiles YES
</code></pre>

<!-- more -->


<p>Right click on Finder, and select Relaunch.</p>

<p>Voila!</p>

<p>Simlarly, to hide the files in Finder, run this:</p>

<pre><code>defaults write com.apple.Finder AppleShowAllFiles NO
</code></pre>

<h2>Bonus: Find all the big files</h2>

<p>One of the reason to show the hidden files is to find all the big files that occupy your disk space.</p>

<p>An easy way is use Finder Search.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Hit Command+F in Finder to bring up the search.</p></li>
<li><p>Click on Others > File Size</p></li>
<li><p>Enter the search criteria eg. greater than 1MB</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="http://cdn.osxdaily.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/find-large-files-mac.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clean install iMac on Mountain Lion]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/03/27/clean-install-imac-on-mountain-lion/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-27T21:54:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/03/27/clean-install-imac-on-mountain-lion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I posted about how I <a href="/2013/02/14/migrating-old-mac-to-new-mac/">migrate an old Mac to a new Mac</a> in a previous post.</p>

<p>After migration, I also wanted to do a clean install on the old Mac, and bring it to factory settings, but with the latest OS X (Mountain Lion for me).</p>

<p>It is very easy.</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote></blockquote>

<p>The steps:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Restart computer and press <strong>Command + R</strong> while it restart to get to a menu screen</p></li>
<li><p>Select <strong>Disk Utility</strong> > Macintosh HD (your startup volume) > Erase</p></li>
<li><p>Go back to menu screen and select <strong>Install Mac OS X</strong></p></li>
</ul>


<p>Follow through and it will be done!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Trackpad 4 finger swipe up/down not working]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/02/15/apple-trackpad-4-finger-not-working/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T00:06:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/02/15/apple-trackpad-4-finger-not-working</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When my new iMac was delivered, the only unsatisfactory I had was with the faulty trackpad. It can click, but can't move the cursor at all! I sent it for servicing and got a replacement after a few days.</p>

<p>Anyway, this post isn't about a new iMac with a faulty trackpad.</p>

<p>What happened is that when I use the new and working trackpad, I realized the 4 finger swipe up/down gestures were not working (therefore I can't do Expose and Mission Control).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The fix is rather trivial:</p>

<p>Go to Preferences > Trackpad > More Gestures > Mission Control and change <strong>Swipe up with four fingers</strong> to <strong>Swipe up with three fingers</strong>.</p>

<p>Try it now and it should work.</p>

<p>Now, change it back to <strong>Swipe up with four fingers</strong>, and it works too!</p>

<p>Do the same trick for App Expose.</p>

<p>Finally, go to Point &amp; Click to re-enable <strong>Three Finger Drag</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating old Mac to new Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/02/14/migrating-old-mac-to-new-mac/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T23:29:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/02/14/migrating-old-mac-to-new-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did a migration using the <strong>Migration Assistant</strong> app when I bought a new iMac (late 2012 27" model).</p>

<p>I decided to migrate everything (instead of a fresh install) as I DON'T want to:</p>

<ul>
<li>reinstall hundreds of apps</li>
<li>setup the system preferences</li>
<li>manually transfer files</li>
</ul>


<p>But migration is not perfect (though I think it is much efficient than doing a fresh install).</p>

<p>Here are some tips that you will be interested to know.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>1. Create a new user with a different username</h2>

<p>In your new iMac, when you start the OS the first time, it is compulsory for you to create a new user account.</p>

<p>This is temporary. Once you migrated, the account will be deleted.</p>

<p>Don't create a user account with the same username as that from the old Mac, as that will cause a conflict, and you have to start over at some point in the migration. This tip could save you 10 minutes.</p>

<h2>2. Transfer medium using cross cable</h2>

<p>This is up to you. For me, I choose to connect the 2 Macs using a cross ethernet cable.</p>

<p>It took 8 hours to migrate nearly 500 GB of data.</p>

<h2>3. Most things are good</h2>

<p>Once migrated, most things are good.</p>

<p>Your applications are there. Your OS settings are intact. Your files are there.</p>

<p>In the next sections, it tells some of the things that were broken.</p>

<h2>4. Dropbox</h2>

<p>Your dropbox folder is there, but it is not synced.</p>

<p>You have to reinstall Dropbox, and they will resync like old times.</p>

<h2>5. Git</h2>

<p>Your <code>git</code> command cannot be recognized. Simply <a href="http://git-scm.com/download/mac">download</a> and install again.</p>

<h2>6. Octopress</h2>

<p>It is best you go through this <a href="http://samwize.com/2012/09/11/how-to-setup-octopress-on-github-pages/">octopress setup guide</a> again.</p>

<p>Explicitly, you do need to install OS X GCC Compiler and bundle install.</p>

<h2>7. Eclipse, and Plugins</h2>

<p>If you open and encounter an error, simply <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/">reinstall</a>. You need to install Google Plugin for Eclipse too if you are using.</p>

<h2>8. More..</h2>

<p>More to be updated as I use my new iMac :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
