<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cloud | Junda Ong]]></title>
  <link href="http://samwize.com/blog/categories/cloud/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://samwize.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-09T23:01:30+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://samwize.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Junda]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[junda@just2us.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[App Engine Unused Discounted Instance Hour]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2012/11/23/app-engine-unused-discounted-instance-hour/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T22:48:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2012/11/23/app-engine-unused-discounted-instance-hour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google App Engine has this item - Discounted Instance Hour - which you can reserve a number of hours per week at a cheaper cost.</p>

<p>Recently, I was looking at the Charge Sent per week, and one of the item is this:</p>

<blockquote><p>Unused Discounted Instance Hour - Used XXX hours</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>The item cost a big part of my weekly charges. I was puzzled at first: How did I used XXX hours out of an item that said is unused?</p>

<p>Then I went to my Billing Settings, and saw this:</p>

<pre><code>Discounted Instance Hours: YYY Hours

Committing to a number of instance hours for a weekly billing period in advance can 
help lower your bill. You will be charged $0.05 per hour for the hours you commit to here, 
even if you don't use them during the billing period.
</code></pre>

<p>I have set YYY hours per week as a <strong>Reserved</strong> Discounted Instance Hours.</p>

<p>Even if I don't use them, they are charged!</p>

<h2>Lesson Learnt</h2>

<p>At times, you should monitor the weekly usage.</p>

<p>If the <strong>Unused Discounted Instance Hour</strong> is very high (much higher than what is being used), then you should adjust it from Billing Settings.</p>

<p>I have wasted quite some money paying for instance hours that I didn't use..</p>

<p>(I set the reserved instance hours very high initially because there was a period of peak, but now it has gone down, yet I didn't adjust..)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GAE or Dotcloud?]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2012/11/21/gae-or-dotcloud/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2012/11/21/gae-or-dotcloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been thinking which to use.</p>

<p>I am already using Google App Engine (Java) for a few years, running a couple of web apps on production. And paying them ever since they started charging.</p>

<p>I tried a few apps on Dotcloud, but never yet deployed any on production.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Here's what I think of them.</p>

<h2>GAE</h2>

<pre><code>+ Reliable
+ Great Docs
+ Great Community
+ On demand scaling

- Some restrictions
- User Agent has GAE..
</code></pre>

<h2>Dotcloud</h2>

<pre><code>+ Shell access
+ Can use pip install
+ Can run worker processes

- Too much things to handle
- Easily use up workers/services - Redis, MySQL, Python, ...
- Higher startup cost
</code></pre>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>As a one-man-show developer, my bet is on GAE.</p>

<p>Though it is less flexible, it will save time and money.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
