<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | Junda Ong]]></title>
  <link href="http://samwize.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://samwize.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-27T00:20:56+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://samwize.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Junda]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good Strategy, Bad Strategy]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2012/10/24/good-strategy-bad-strategy/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T22:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2012/10/24/good-strategy-bad-strategy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a review of the book <a href="http://www.bookdepository.co.uk/Good-Strategybad-Strategy-Richard-Rumelt/9781846684814?a_aid=Just2me">Good Strategy, Bad Strategy</a>.</p>

<p>The first 20% of the book is still okay. But I could not read beyond that, as it is long winded, and used too many examples from US Military strategies.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, here's what I learnt:</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>The Problem</h3>

<p>Definition of Strategy - We don't really understand it.</p>

<p>Confused, and "strategy" became a verbal tic. eg. IT Strategy, Low-price Strategy, ...</p>

<p>A word that can mean anything has lost its bite.</p>

<p>We need a redefintion. A real understanding of Strategy.</p>

<h3>Core of strategy work</h3>

<p>= Discover critical factor in a situation + Design a way of coordinating and focusing actions
= Recognise Challenges + Approach to overcome them</p>

<p>A <strong>leader's most important responsibility</strong> is working on strategy.</p>

<p>Mastering the shift from others defining your goals, to being the architect of the organisation purposes and objectives.</p>

<h3>A good strategy</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Selects the path, identifying the how, why and where leadership and determination are to be applied</p></li>
<li><p>Say "NO" to wide variety of actions and interests</p></li>
<li><p>It's as much as what an organisation does not do, as what it does</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Why so much bad strategy?</p>

<p>Strategy involves focus, and choice; Most people have unwillness or inability to choose</p>

<h3>Kernel</h3>

<p>A logical structure:</p>

<p>1) Diagnosis - Simplify and identify the critical</p>

<p>2) Guiding policy - Overall approach</p>

<p>3) Coherent actions - Steps that work together</p>

<p>Example (Apple by Steve Jobs in 1998):</p>

<blockquote><p>Challenge: Product lineup was too complicated. Too many price points and too much markup.</p>

<p>Action: Cut all except 1 laptop, Cut distributors, Cut development</p></blockquote>

<p>When PC is dominated by Microsoft, Apple Strategy is "to wait for the next big thing"</p>

<p>Apple eventually released the iPhone</p>

<h3>What I didn't read..</h3>

<p>After finished Part I, I merely browsed Part II and III..</p>

<p>Part II - Sources of Power - I don't read. Not necessary. Using leverage, advantage, dynamics, focus, growth, etc..</p>

<p>Part III - Not sure what's the conclusion</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Lean Startup]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2012/10/11/the-lean-startup/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-11T00:08:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2012/10/11/the-lean-startup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bookdepository.co.uk/Lean-Startup-Eric-Ries/9780670921607?a_aid=Just2me">The Lean Startup</a> is about a scientific approach to managing startups/entrepreneurs.</p>

<p>It is recommended that anyone working in a startup stop whatever they are doing, and spent the next 24 hours to complete the book.</p>

<p>I will be summarizing some great concepts that I have learnt.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.bookdepository.co.uk/Lean-Startup-Eric-Ries/9780670921607?a_aid=Just2me"><img class="center" src="/images/book-the-lean-startup.jpeg"></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Introduction: Why We Fail</h2>

<p>In traditional management, when you fail, there are only 2 possible explanations:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Fail to plan</p></li>
<li><p>Fail to execute</p></li>
</ol>


<p>But what if you fail because your <strong>hypothesis is wrong</strong> in the first place?</p>

<p>An execution of a perfect plan, based on a flawed idea, would only fail.</p>

<p>The book focus on testing hypothesis and fine-tuning it, in a scientific way.</p>

<h2>Build-Measure-Learn Cycle</h2>

<p>There is usually an hypothesis to an idea, a feature, a marketing plan, a business model, or <em>anything that the customer touches</em>.</p>

<p>We always <em>assume</em> how customer will react.</p>

<p>Hence the need of this cycle/iteration:</p>

<ul>
<li>Build MVP (a Minimum Viable Product)</li>
<li>Measure data</li>
<li>Learn the goods and bads</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/images/build-measure-learn-cycle.png"></p>

<p>The process is actually reverse; You start with planning what you want to learn, what you need to measure, then build it small and ASAP - the eventual MVP.</p>

<p>Our job is to find a synthesis between our vision and what the customers would accept. Iterate and find the balance.</p>

<h2>MVP = The Fears</h2>

<p>We always argue about building MVP.</p>

<p>There is usually constant debate among team members on 2 accounts:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Fear of low quality/inferior product</p></li>
<li><p>Fear of idea being stolen</p></li>
</ol>


<p>But, if we do not know who the customer is, <strong>we do not know what quality is</strong>!</p>

<p>If only it is so easy to get good ideas stolen! The challenge of startup is getting your product noticed by <em>anyone</em>, let alone a competitor.</p>

<p>Even if the idea gets stolen, the only way for either your competitor or you to win is - to learn faster than anyone else. For that, you have a headstart.</p>

<h2>Measure - Innovative Accounting</h2>

<p>Traditional numbers are "Vanity Metrics". eg. total number of users, total active users</p>

<p>It's not measuring the Growth Engine.</p>

<p>Startup is about Growth, and the Engine that drives it. Therefore you must and should measure that, and identify it.</p>

<p>Techniques: Cohorts, split test, A/B testing</p>

<p>Make Data part of the product.</p>

<p>3 A's of the Data:</p>

<ol>
<li>Actionable Metric = clear cause and effect</li>
<li>Accessible = Everyone can access and understand in layman terms</li>
<li>Auditable = Talking to customer</li>
</ol>


<h2>Pivot</h2>

<p>There is no way to remove human element - vision, intuition, judgement.</p>

<p>Some people are better because they have talent or experience. But it is inevitable for a pivot. It is not a big deal anyway, if you understood why you need a pivot in the first place.</p>

<p>Have regular <strong>Pivot Or Persevere</strong> meeting. Especially if there is telltale signs.</p>

<p>Types of pivot:</p>

<ol>
<li>Zoom-in Pivot</li>
<li>Zoom-out Pivot</li>
<li>Customer Segment Pivot</li>
<li>Customer Needs Pivot</li>
<li>Platform Pivot</li>
<li>Business Architecture Pivot</li>
<li>Value Capture Pivot</li>
<li>Engine of Growth Pivot</li>
<li>Channel Pivot</li>
<li>Technology Pivot</li>
</ol>


<p>Pivot itself is a hypothesis, though a strategic one.</p>

<p>Pivot is a structural change designed to test a fundamental hypothesis about a product, business model, and growth engine.</p>

<p>Startup's Runway = Number of Pivots it can still make</p>

<h2>Growth Engine</h2>

<p><strong>Sustainable Growth</strong> = New customers come from the actions of past customers</p>

<p>3 types of growth engine:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Sticky Engine = Customer retention</p></li>
<li><p>Viral Engine = Spread socially</p></li>
<li><p>Paid Engine = Self funded by advertising</p></li>
</ol>


<p>There are obviously other engines.</p>

<p>Focus on one engine at a time (to build-measure-learn).</p>

<h2>Five Whys</h2>

<p>Ask "Why" five times to understand the root of the problem.</p>

<p>Solve a problem in stages, with incremental improvements.</p>

<p>But there is curse of the 5 blames.. Remember, it's not about blaming. It's about improving the system process.</p>

<p>Two simplified rules:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Be tolerant on the first mistake</p></li>
<li><p>Never allow the same mistake to be made twice</p></li>
</ol>


<h2>Waste not</h2>

<p>Building products that customers doesn't want is a big waste.</p>

<p>In this 21st century, we now have supreme productive capacity and technology. We should change our question from</p>

<blockquote><p>Can it be built?</p></blockquote>

<p>to</p>

<blockquote><p>Should it be built?</p></blockquote>

<p>We would achieve much greater heights, if our economy is not wasteful.</p>

<h2>Other Thoughts</h2>

<p>Traditionally, definition of productivity is by functional excellence. Example, a programmer is expected to code all day.</p>

<p>That's why programmers hate meetings. But to achieve validated learning, an individual must cross-function.</p>

<p>Have small, cross-functional team.</p>

<p>Optimization Vs Learning: Some of the features are merely optimization. It improves the product, but marginally. It is demoralizing when that happens.</p>

<p>In traditional management, when senior management don't see results, they assume the team did not work hard enough, or not good enough. This is when personnel changes and musical chair is being played.</p>

<p>Organisation has Muscle Memory. It is not easy to change the habits of a company. You are up against a system and individuals' changes. It's tough to implement the methods, but it's for the good.</p>

<h2>What should you do?</h2>

<p>After reading the book, I ask myself what should I do?</p>

<p>Hope you ask too, and come to the same conclusion as me - to <em>validate</em> the teachings of The Lean Startup.</p>

<p>Think of a minimum change you can introduced, change it, then measure and learn.</p>

<p><em>PS: If you enjoy, buy the book with my <a href="http://www.bookdepository.co.uk/Lean-Startup-Eric-Ries/9780670921607?a_aid=Just2me">bookdepository affiliate link</a> (:</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
