<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: iOS | Junda Ong]]></title>
  <link href="http://samwize.com/blog/categories/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://samwize.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-02T20:51:40+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://samwize.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Junda]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[junda@just2us.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC 2013 - download sessions directly]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/07/02/wwdc-2013-download-sessions-directly/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-02T00:54:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/07/02/wwdc-2013-download-sessions-directly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Unlike in previous years (WWDC 2012 and earlier), the developer session videos can be subscribed in iTunes University, hence you can easily download all the videos and conveniently sync to your iPhone to watch.</p>

<p>But for WWDC 2013, Apple provided (an app)[https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/wwdc/id640199958?mt=8], which seems to be the recommended way for developers to watch from their iPhone.</p>

<p>You can also download 1 by 1 from <a href="https://developer.apple.com/wwdc/videos/">Apple Developer website</a>.
‎
But here is a better: <a href="https://github.com/ohoachuck/wwdc-downloader">WWDC Video and PDF downloder</a> by <a href="http://blog.hoachuck.biz/blog/2013/06/15/script-to-download-wwdc-2013-videos">ohoachuck</a>.</p>

<p>Or a <a href="http://blog.manbolo.com/2013/06/18/download-videos-and-slides-from-wwdc-2013">Python version</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Data Storage Guidelines - and how to resolve iTunes Connect Reject]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/06/28/ios-data-storage-guidelines-and-how-to-resolve-itunes-connect-reject/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-28T01:10:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/06/28/ios-data-storage-guidelines-and-how-to-resolve-itunes-connect-reject</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since the introduction of <a href="https://www.apple.com/support/icloud/backup/">iCloud Backup</a>, developers have increasingly faced the following reason for rejected binary:</p>

<pre><code>2.23: Apps must follow the iOS Data Storage Guidelines or they will be rejected

The iOS Data Storage Guidelines indicate that only content that the user creates using your app, e.g., documents, new files, edits, etc., should be backed up by iCloud. 
</code></pre>

<p>This all boils down to understanding <a href="http://developer.apple.com/library/ios/#documentation/iPhone/Conceptual/iPhoneOSProgrammingGuide/PerformanceTuning/PerformanceTuning.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40007072-CH8-SW9">iOS Data Storage Guidelines</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>How App Backup and Update</h1>

<p>Apps are backup via iCloud/iTunes, but they do NOT backup the following directories:</p>

<ol>
<li><code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/AppName.app</code></li>
<li><code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/Library/Caches</code></li>
<li><code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/tmp</code></li>
</ol>


<p>In addition, if a file has an attribute that says "exclude from backup", it will NOT be backup too.</p>

<p>When you update an application, data in these 2 directories will be copied over:</p>

<ol>
<li><code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/Documents</code></li>
<li><code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/Library</code></li>
</ol>


<p>Although files in other user directories may also be moved over, you should not rely on them being present after an update.</p>

<h1>Type of data - Critical, Support, Cached, Temporary</h1>

<p>Before we move on, these are the definitions for the 4 types of data:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Critical</strong>: Data that cannot be recreated by your app such as user generated content. These need to be backup.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Support</strong>: Needed files which the app can re-generate or download. They should be excluded from backup.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Cached</strong>: Downloaded content such as images, map data, magazine. System could delete them to free up disk space.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Temporary</strong>: Data that are needed for a short while such as during processing. You should delete them after use.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>As you see, only critical data should be backup.</p>

<h1>Different iOS Version</h1>

<p>There are 3 versions that you <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/#qa/qa1719/_index.html">need to beware of</a> when you are using iCloud Backup. It is a fragmentation issue.</p>

<p>Actually it deals with what files you do NOT want to backup. Because if you simply backup every files (including non critical files), Apple will reject your app.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>5.1 and later: You can add a file attribute <code>NSURLIsExcludedFromBackupKey</code> to specify that you don't want to backup the file.</p></li>
<li><p>5.0.1: A slightly different method that uses <code>setxattr</code></p></li>
<li><p>5.0: No method to specify a file not to backup. The only way is to store them in <code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/Library/Caches</code></p></li>
</ol>


<h1>Summary</h1>

<p>At last, this is the guideline for your files.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>For <strong>critcal</strong> data (the only type that need to be backup), store them in:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/Documents</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>For <strong>support</strong> data, they should be excluded from backup. It is a little complicated due to the different iOS version.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>For iOS 5.0.1 and later, store in <code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/Library/Application Support</code> and add the file attribute as described in the previous section.</p></li>
<li><p>If you need to support iOS 5.0, then store in <code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/Library/Caches</code> and still use the file attributes for 5.0.1 and later</p></li>
<li><p>Note: Support files might not exist when an app backup or update, so you should check if it exists first before use.</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>For <strong>cache</strong>, store in</p>

<ul>
<li><code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/Library/Caches</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>For <strong>temp</strong> files, store in</p>

<ul>
<li><code>&lt;Application_Home&gt;/tmp</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crash when using ChartboostInterstitialCustomEvent in MoPub: unrecognized selector requestAdWithSize]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/06/14/crash-when-using-chartboostinterstitialcustomevent-in-mopub-unrecognized-selector-requestadwithsize/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-14T00:50:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/06/14/crash-when-using-chartboostinterstitialcustomevent-in-mopub-unrecognized-selector-requestadwithsize</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While integrating <a href="https://chartboost.com/">Chartboost</a> into <a href="http://mopub.com/">MoPub</a> for an iOS app, I encountered a crash every time there is a Chartboost ad loading.</p>

<p>The error is:</p>

<pre><code>ChartboostInterstitialCustomEvent requestAdWithSize customEventInfo unrecognized selector 
</code></pre>

<!-- more -->


<p>I thought it is a bug with MoPub at first (my experience tells me as MMedia crashes at times too).</p>

<p>After researching a while, I found out the crash is because MoPub tried to load a banner ad, while Chartboost does not have banner ads! Chartboost ONLY has interstitial ads!</p>

<p>To solve, you have to disable banner ads in MoPub portal for Chartboost..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remember to enable iAd for new iOS apps after uploading binary]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/06/12/remember-to-enable-iad-for-new-ios-apps-after-uploading-binary/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T01:16:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/06/12/remember-to-enable-iad-for-new-ios-apps-after-uploading-binary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can enable iAd network ONLY when your app is in an editable state. That is after uploading binary and before being approved.</p>

<p>If not, you can't.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/enable-iads-when-app-is-in-editable-state.png"></p>

<p>I am not sure how many developers forgot to enable iAd. But I am one. And I blatantly forgot to enable 1 app for over a year.. (I also use Admob, Mopub, MMedia, etc)</p>

<p>Why can't we just flick the switch?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix cocoapod error: the platform of the target pods is not compatible]]></title>
    <link href="http://samwize.com/2013/06/09/fix-cocoapod-error-the-platform-of-the-target-pods-is-not-compatible/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-09T22:46:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://samwize.com/2013/06/09/fix-cocoapod-error-the-platform-of-the-target-pods-is-not-compatible</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While using <a href="http://cocoapods.org/">Cocoapod</a> and running <code>pod install</code>, I encountered the following error:</p>

<pre><code>[!] The platform of the target `Pods` (iOS 4.3) is not compatible with `FlatUIKit (1.1)` which has a minimum requirement of iOS 5.0.
</code></pre>

<!-- more -->


<p>There is obviously a dependency error. Immediately, I open Xcode, go to Project Building Settings, and changed <strong>iOS Deployment Target</strong> to 5.0. I was pretty sure that is the way to change the minimum deployment version.</p>

<p>However, running the command gives me the same error.</p>

<p>I was puzzled. Did I set it wrongly in Xcode? I started to question myself..</p>

<p>After some probing, I realized it is Cocoapod's <a href="https://github.com/CocoaPods/CocoaPods/issues/603">fault</a>.</p>

<p>You have to write in <code>Podfile</code> your minimum deployment version eg.</p>

<p><code>
platform :ios, '5.0'
pod 'FlatUIKit', '~&gt; 1.1'
</code></p>

<p>If you don't specify '5.0', it is taken to be '4.3'. Duh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
